- Montreal, Canada
- +1 (579) 421-7553
- Inkedin.com/in/chioma
- English, Igbo, French

# CHIOMA EMEAKAMA

# **Software Developer**

## **PROFILE**

Solution-driven woman, with strong aptitude for innovation and adaptability in diverse work environments. have over a year's intensive experience in software development through academics, as well as personal projects of both web applications and mobile apps. I am both frontend and backend using different technologies, including React, JavaScript, Java, HTML5, CSS3, REST API, etc. I possess strong problem-solving and analytical skills, I communicate very effectively, and I'm a collaborative team player with strong leadership skills. I am excited at the face of each new challenging opportunity to contribute, to profer solutions using my skills, and to grow personally in this industry.

### **EDUCATION**

PROGRAMMING AND INTERNET TECHNOLOGIES, Attestation of Collegial studies (ACS)

2022 - 2024

College Universel, Montreal

MATHEMATICS, Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) Federal University of Technology Owerri, Nigeria

2013 - 2018

#### **SKILLS**

- **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, Java EE/SE, SQL, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, C#, C++.
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, NetBeans, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Github Issues, Trello, Asana, PowerShell. Maven, TOMCAT, Github, ESLint, Figma, Canya
- Relational Database Management Systems
- Excellent time management skills and orderliness
- Excellent verbal, and non-verbal communication skills

- Design: UI/UX
- Structure: MVC, MVVM,
- Patterns/ Architecture: Object Oriented Programming, Agile Methodology (Scrum), Data Structures and Algorithms.
- · Self-motivated leader, able to work well under pressure.
- · Excellent Interpersonal Skills
- Excellent team player and problem solving skills.
- · Adaptability and eagerness to learn

### **PROJECTS**

React - Movie Mayen August 2023

- Movie Maven is a movie search web application where a user can search for a movie by name, category, and any other key word of their choice. One can also rent a movie, see the likes and ratings of that movie, like a movie, rate a movie, and comment to review a movie as well. This was a (Group Project).
- I implemented the rental functionality, as well as a signup page for the app.
- · We had daily scrum meetings through the project, and Asana was used as the project management tool.
- Developed using Android studio, using Java languages, and Gradle as the dependency manager.

Java EE - EconoMe August 2023

- Developed an android financial budget application called EconoMe, which can be used on dynamic sized smart android gadgets, which allows the user to plan their budgets in categories, and track expenditures monthly. (Group Project).
- Implemented the record interface which accumulates all transactions in the application using the CRUD operations.
- Managed version control and tracked tasks progress using GitHub.
- · Developed using Android studio, using Java languages, and Gradle as the dependency manager.

Java - Online Store

- Built a dynamic online shopping cart which allows users to select items in a gallery, edit selection, and make payment using Java, HTML and CSS.
- Deployed the use of servlets and achieved the dynamic nature of the app using JSP, and TOMCAT as the dependency manager in the Apache Netbeans IDE.

June 2023

### JavaScript - Hangman

- Developed a game which allows users to guess a word from different categories, with a diagrammatic number of trials, called the hangman (6 trials), after which the word will be displayed if lost. (Solo Project)
- · Developed using HTML CSS, and JavaScript in Visual Studio Code.

### **EXPERIENCES**

#### **IT SUPPORT Intern**

July 2016 - February 2017

ABC TRANSPORT PLC, Nigeria

- Carried out installation services, database management and role assignment to software users.
- Executed hardware maintenance and repairs.
- · Managed the company's database and website administration.
- · Maintained the company's networks (WLAN and LAN).
- Profered hardware repairs/ replacement solutions.

TEACHER March 2019 - March 2020

GDSS Mansur, Nigeria

- Developed innovative teaching methodologies to simplify complex mathematical concepts to their understanding.
- Created engaging and structured math lesson plans, demonstrating strong organizational skills and attention to detail.
- Utilized data-driven assessment techniques to track student progress and adjust teaching strategies accordingly.
- Spearheaded school-wide STEM competitions, igniting a passion for knowledge and innovation among students while cultivating a growth mindset; nurturing a culture of continuous learning and self-improvement in students.

#### **CREW MEMBER**

Five Guys, Montreal December 2022 - present

- Worked cohesively within a fast-paced environment, adapted to high-pressure situations and resolved customer issues promptly and diplomatically, resulting in 10% increase in positive reviews online for the company.
- Quickly addressed customer issues, found solutions on the spot and adapted to high-pressure situations during peak dining hours.
- Participated in quality control checks to maintain food quality standards and efficiently managed orders, ensuring
  qualitative and timely delivery to customers which reduced food waste by 80%, causing profit.